August J Yadon

Cleveland, OH • (408) 609 0996 • AugustYadon@gmail.com

Gameplay Programmer

C# Game developer, with an arsenal of tech experience and a thirst for learning.

As a critical thinker, I'll usually step back and think, what is our actual goal here; is this the most practical way to accomplish this goal, or is this just our first idea? Are we choosing the technology for the solution we need, or are we bending our solution unnecessarily to fit our technology stack?

Technology tools include:

- C#
- SteamVR Plugin
- Unity 3D
- Steamworks libraries
- JS/Node.is
 Git/SVN/Perforce
- AR Kit / AR Core / AR Foundations
- iOS and Android Development
- Face Detection with Dlib
- AR (Augmented Reality)
- VR (Virtual Reality)
- SQL / Mongo DB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wheedle, (Remote) Los Angeles, CA

Lead AR Developer - Contract (November 2018 - November 2019) [Unity, Dlib, C#/C++]

R&D ways to utilize Unity to bring face recognition to AR glasses for. Multiple Successful Prototypes.

AIR EVERYWHERE, Kent, OH

Lead AR Developer III (October 2018 – July 2019) [C#, Unity, AR Kit/ARCore/ARFoundation, Mapbox]

Took conceptual ideas from the business side, and architected and built them into a reality.

- Led a team and challenged initial ideas to move them into an AR state of mind.
- Handled most of the physics based pieces, and 3D vector based problems.
- Improved the user experience with sounds/haptics/responsive interactions/mechanics.

REWIND.SITE, (Remote) NYC, NY

Backend Developer - Contract (June 2018 - October 2018) [C++, Source Engine]

Completed tasks to bring new features to a CS:GO Demo Viewer platform

AUGGO DOGGO GAMES, Cleveland, OH

Gameplay Programmer (January 2017 – Present) [C#, Node.js, Unity, Vive/Oculus]

Created VR game - Plunker - Indie game development was performed entirely on Twitch.TV live.

- Created development tools, and powerful algorithms necessary for certain game mechanics.
- Created, textured, rigged, animated, voiced/audio engineered, and programmed all 3D assets.

NIMBLEFISH TECHNOLOGIES, San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer II (December 2014 – January 2017) [Node.js - Java - Bash]

GENERAL DYNAMICS, San Francisco Bay Area, CA

Hardware Programmer (October 2012 – December 2014) [C, C++, Bash, QA]

EDUCATION

CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY, Cleveland, OH – B.S. in Electrical Engineering, 2012